oh I hear myself but um you know you got
the accessories sitting on the wall and
they don't move anywhere um so and then
you got cheap phones that maybe not a
lot of people want to buy how did you
flip those phones like what how did you
you know push cheap products on people
so that you can get to that next level
where did you get the Sound Skills from
all right well let me let me rephrase
the word it wasn't cheap products it was
inexpensive phones there's there is
there price range
and where I'm from it's an area where
you have either drug dealers or you have
people who can't afford the highend
products so they spend $100 on the phone
right and the $100 phone includes the
you know the the the the phone and the
service right so the cost for the first
month of service was literally probably
Zer which meant that in my business I
just so you know Ryan I did prepaid
phones I didn't do po uh postpaid I
think what you're talking about is more
on the postpaid uh postpaid carriers
right right now I did prepaid so there's
a little bit higher profit margin but
just on on the front end not the back
end postpaid you have more money on the
back end and that's just between you and
I because we both know the industry
right
so prepaid cheap cheap entry um
inexpensive entry but it's still a
business I didn't have accessories on
the wall I had a cart in the mall it all
started at a cart not not even actual
store I didn't get my first store until
six months after so it was a it was a
cart in the mall so the it was very
inexpensive for me to start I had to
hustle now how we started selling was um
greeting customers I have I have a
technique where I can get a customer
who's say 50 feet away from me to get
them to come over here and I will give
you that technique right now but it's
for your viewers and I've never done
this on a Facebook live before but I'm
going do it for your viewers
it happens it happens in real life so
this is what I would do I would whisper
so I would I would do just
this and I would look at the person as
if I'm saying
something and and they say they say what
I say no what I was saying I I would
talk loud and I would drift my voice
down so what I was saying was when he
come and they' be like what did you say
and when they get actually closer to me
I was saying I work at a cell phone
store what phone do you have and they be
like I have an iPhone 6 and I'm going to
pretend like I don't know what iPhone 6
is right so they would be like I have an
iPhone 6 I was like iPhone 6 you have it
with you and I would look at at their
wallet or the purse or whatever they
they're holding and they like yeah and
they they'll show it to me I I'll say
let me see that and I'll grab it out of
their hand and I would look at the phone
like this I'll say oh iPhone 6 I will
grab it keep holding on to it and bring
it to my car put it behind my computer
and now I'm doing my pitch I'm 19 years
old teaching people how to do that I'll
grab it put it behind my computer now
I'm doing my now you would have some
[ __ ] people that are like give my
[ __ ] phone back and and and I and I
give them the phone back but you have
some people who are actually listening
and then after that do my pitch and I'll
sell them on something else so where did
you get those those those skills from I
mean like I I was in sales even from
when I was 12 so you kind of learn from
watching other people but like was it
just you being really hungry and just
trying to find multiple ways of of of
getting that getting that dough or you
know like how did you how did you get
that smart to be able to you know to
kind of wheel them into um listening to
you and talking to
you I I was mentored by somebody who was
my manager because remember I was
working at a Metro PCS before I open
been on my own spot so I was already
selling phones and that's part of the
strategy that you needed to to to to to
cell phones and now in addition to that
someone taught me the whisper technique
right it taught me the whisper technique
but after the whisper technique I I had
to figure out how do I get them to stay
because they would come to me with the
whisper after the whisper technique and
then they
leave I think I froze am I Frozen you're
not
frozen okay I hope hey I need y to
comment I need y'all to comment I I need
I know I know you're like you know
you're like like like I know you like
the story but I need y'all a comment
show some love show some love at the
bottom say what's up Andy show some love
at the bottom now so I learned I learned
about this technique The Whisper right
and after the whisper I I did my own
type of uh finessing into it where I got
people to stay by taking their phone and
placing it behind the register U not
allowing them to take the phone back so
now if if you are in the mall walking
and someone does this to you and they
that you're you're actually there you're
actually there to take your phone you're
about to be sold another thing that I
would do if I don't have the phone in my
hand I would do this I would say man I
got something just for you turn around
and do this and never look back if you
look back that means you are not
confident the most confident person in
the in the sales negotiation wins so you
got to turn around and keep walking as
if they're walking behind you and you
know like some people might not follow
you that's okay just turn around and
boom as soon as you start walking what
happens is that people are like am I am
I really going to follow this guy like
he's not and and they walk behind me and
that's when I would do the pitch now I
got them to my zone into my store okay
that's what I would do wow that's crazy
and I think you like you're pretty good
at sales and I mean and I and I and I
can tell you
firsthand um in uh coming into one I I
think I was in one of of your lives and
you said you you you saw me in the chat
and you're like my May Ryan perz Ryan
Perez what's going on my man and then
you're like I got a book just for you
and you signed it and everything and
he's like 29.99 or whatever the thing is
and you know you had your sales pitch
but you know I when I saw that I was
like man that reminds me still waiting
for you to buy the book
man I was like you know what cuz it made
it what the way that you made it sound
like I was going to in it for free and I
was like man that is so nice to this guy
to be
like he signs the book and like you know
but but I I said to
[Music]
what's going on folks it's me again you
guys are probably sick and tired of all
of these lives that we've been doing but
uh folks welcome to the hustle Zone my
name is Ryan Perez I owner and founder
of bowai creative and host of The Hustle
Zone and you know we did a
record-breaking live yesterday we did
three-hour live we did the hustle Zone
trivia and I think that that was great I
think uh my co-host Monica was pretty
awesome um but we we're going to be
testing out the that sort of live um
ever so often uh just to kind of see
what what format's going to work for
those trivas because we definitely want
to give people a break uh from you know
just all the motivation rah rah rah and
then the depressing here's my story um
and you know kind of give people a
little bit uh you know something a
little bit different but like I said my
name is Ryan Perez and I am the owner of
B creative so make sure you guys check
out ww. creative we are a company that
does more we have solutions that do more
websites that do more um we build online
businesses anytime I hear people talk
about websites I cringe because websit
is just like handing me a brochure I
mean who who who like prints brochures
anymore man everything is in um in
digital um the next thing is we just
launched branding jim.com and branding
Jim is a company that does unlimited
graphic design so um super excited about
this company so if you guys have any
questions um just let me know and then
of course we have hustles on.tv the
world's first living documentary where
we we where we uh interview
entrepreneurs about their stories so we
reveal more right that's why I always
tell my guests you know this is not the
uh this is not the the the the episode
where we talk about mindset and
motivation this is this is me asking you
about your story and really giving
people a different view of the type of
person you are behind all the great you
know photos that you have and the great
you know lives that you do on Zoom you
know we want to get the best um story
and good stories are unique to you so um
you guys definitely want to uh check
that out and we got a gofund me we got
GoFundMe account um you know we're
looking for some donations so that we
can continue on with this documentary so
ww. gofundme.com
hustle zoney TV check us out and reason
why you want to donate with us document
stories okay so we're documenting
stories like our guest tonight um we
also give free education so everyone
that is charging $99.97 for the secrets
of success I'm giving away all that
information for free because I really
want to encourage the Youth of the
future to become entrepreneurs um you
know giving them a different path and
that goes to my second Point developing
future entrepreneurs even if you're
young or old you know it's never too
late to get into entrepreneurship and
then we want to provide honest content
so we put your comments on your on on
the screen so if you want to fact check
things that I've said things that my
guests have said we will display it on
the screen so that's live um live uh um
factchecking and where does all the
money go to again and I
apologize this is the wrong graphic
because it should be 50% but 50% it's
going to go into employees uh 15 or 15%
will go into travel 5% will go go into
admin uh 15% legal and 15% Tech so
um uh so that's pretty that's pretty
much it and
um now I think my guest is frozen I
don't know if he is still
there um looks like my guest is Frozen
um are you still there andy
okay oh and then we got a lot of people
in the room so I'm going to let I'm
going to wait for Andy to come in um I'm
not sure uh it seems like he's Frozen uh
seems like there's a really bad internet
connection so I'm just going to give him
some time to um see if he can come back
in um I'm going to um just address some
of the people that are in the room right
now so give me a few seconds folks while
I log in to um so who all like put in
the comment section who all has come
into the
um um who all has come into the the live
from
yesterday okay looks like our guest is
back so um all right we're just having
some um technical issues folks so um if
anything we will edit this out in the um
in the post production but who who all
was in the uh uh
uh in the live last night it was 3 and a
half hours uh yeah I got I I can hear
you
um and shout out to real Bush thank you
so much for for coming into the live uh
we got Rachel Johnson in the house thank
you for coming out Rachel and then we
got Susan day Susan day my she's the
hustle Zone Queen she's been here from
the very beginning so you know it's been
a it's been over a year Susan since
we've been doing this stuff so you know
I really uh appreciate you for coming in
on the live tonight and folks feel free
to comment I'm going to put those
comments on the
screen okay awesome so we got um we got
Simon in the house as well so this is
going to be awesome so let me tell you a
little bit about my
guest okay so my guest is
um I I
I just seen him around because you know
obviously this is a really you know even
though this is a big world I live in
Canada he's out in um uh he's out in
right now he's traveling he's out in in
in New York but I would see a lot of his
stuff around you know he's a clean
polished young entrepreneur and you know
he's doing some big things I mean he was
uh he put on a conference not too long
go and you know when I was 17 years old
you know and I I changed my life around
one of the people that I would listen to
on Napster see I think I'm too old cuz I
don't even think my guest even knows
what Napster is because that was where
we were the file sharing Etc but I was I
was downloading um you know Tony Robins
Zig Ziggler and I was uh downloading Les
Brown and Les Brown a lot of the things
that he said had transformed my life you
know and lo and behold here's a young
guy that is 22 years old he is a
accomplished author and he's also a uh
you know he's a motivational speaker but
he's 22 years old you know and he got to
meet a guy that I idolized for you know
nearly I would say over over like close
to 15 years you know so you know he's
living He living a bit of my dream cuz I
wanted to do like a speaking engagement
with with Les Brown so I I found it
really fascinating that he was able to
put on the conference and and to do all
of that so I'm super happy to have our
guest on tonight and um so I want you
guys to give it up for Mr Andy a date
how's it going my brother hold on one
second here I love that you love it he I
love that and I love it I love it oh man
you Real Canadian man you said the a at
the end he love it yeah I'm a real
Canadian someone called me out on that
the other day they're like hey I heard
you say hey and I'm like man CH I we my
parents are from the Caribbean so
sometimes we say I hear people say a and
then some people in in in the states say
a as well but you know when you hear it
from Canada you know people have to
point it out but uh how are you doing my
brother you're up late you know you're
in the Hampton dog like you're living it
up man God all I know is God is good man
I'm do I'm doing God's work that's what
I know okay I and um I I know that there
may be a delay so um so folks bear with
us uh so
Andy um tell us a little bit about your
book before we get started into our
interview man I'm I'm super pumped and
I'm super excited okay because I just
I'm relaunching my book right now so my
original book is called No More average
right and it's about overcoming the
averageness and it defines what average
is when people say like hey you know
this guy's average like what is that and
what does that mean it defines it but
I'm pumped because I haven't even seen
my my my relaunched book yet I haven't
actually seen the physical copy and I
I'm GNA be at an event on on I'm right
now in New York I live in Los Angeles
I'm going to be at an event in in New
York on Wednesday so I ordered the book
to the hotel so on Tuesday I'm going to
actually have the physical copy when I'm
at the hotel so I'm pumped up I'm
excited for that but but no more average
is about overcoming that average life
and experiencing life as the real you
what God has intended for your life to
be like what I believe God has intended
for your life to be like awesome now uh
folks before we get started please this
is a special occasion see I went and put
on a
sweater I love it button up the shirt
for this young guy he's showing us all
up so we had I had to make sure I shaved
and I was looking fresh and clean um oh
and the comments are no longer showing
on the screen which is okay uh but
either way so
Andy oh yeah sorry before I you guys got
to share this because this is this is
this is uh you know history in the
making because I think that one of these
days you know Mr Andy is going to be
really famous and I think we're all
going to know his name he's going to be
a household name so you know make sure
you guys uh share this uh this feed for
tonight um and um and like like like you
know show us your love show us your your
interactivity um just so that we can
have some some energy in the room
tonight and um and make sure that if you
guys can't watch this episode you can
always go on to our website hustlez
own.tv or you can go and see us in our
or you can hear us um on iTunes so okay
Andy so we have a tradition on the
hustle Zone and this wouldn't be the
hustle Zone if I didn't ask you this
first
question now um and it's an open-ended
question what is your story so before
your success before all the public
speaking you know you know and and I
mean you have 22e span you know start
from the very beginning you know how did
you grow up like who are you
I was born it all started when I was
born in Boston Massachusetts I was born
in the bean Town my mom was watching
Oprah right she's pregnant at the time
my mom's watching Oprah and gush like I
don't knowwhere her water breaks and my
aunt is with her at the house and he's
like oh shoot it's time let's go to the
hospital and we so they're going to the
hospital of course I'm in my mom's belly
at the time and my mom's driving the car
my M my aunt is driving in the car to
the hospital but but my aunt is
panicking and she's looking at my mom
and she's like Gina my mom's name is
Gina she's like looking at my mom she
like Gina are you okay like she's
freaking out and she's freaking out more
than my mom is my mom's like you know
calm she's cool she's Collective and I
think that's where I get my calmness
coolness and Collective from is from my
mom who's just calm in in situation
situations of disarray and you know in a
few hours I was born I was born December
31st the last day
am I am I still good yeah you're still
good go ahead okay I was born on
December 31st the last day of the year
but you know it was it was a blessing
after that seven years later I moved
from Boston to Rhode Island and I'm I'm
just an average seveny year get it
average I'm just an average seveny old
kid at the time and I wanted things you
know I wanted the things that my friends
had and I spent many years wanting these
items these things that my friends had
which it could have been the Xbox it
could have been the the shoes the
clothes The Bling Bling the money all
these little material things four years
four years after that I'm 11 years old I
say to my mom look I'm tired of not
getting the things that I want I'm gonna
go out and make it happen how you gonna
do that Mom I'm gonna go knock knock on
every single door and I'm gonna ask them
if I can shovel it a yard make some
money that way so that's what I started
in in the in the winter I would shovel
people snow get $10 a pop in the summer
I would have lemonade stands and do yard
sales then I started realizing the the
the the the the like the the
consciousness of money I started
realizing like if I do something for
someone else I make money after after at
11 years after 11 years old I'm doing
that for a few years I get a job at 16
years old and I just work work hustle
hustle for money hustle for money I was
15 years old I was 16 and I bought
before I bought had my license I bought
a $500 car I had $3,000 or whatever it
was at 16 years old I was just focused
on getting what I what I wanted at 19
years old I had a friend of mine who I
was working with at a cell phone store
we were both working at a cell phone
store he said to me he said Andy I
believe in you I think you should quit
and open up your own cell phone store I
said you know what let's do it at 19
years old I opened up my first cell pH
cell phone store and that that person
who told me I brought him on to my
by 20 years old I had four locations and
um 14 employees and at 21 I moved from
Los an from Rhode Island to Los Angeles
and now I'm still developing the
remainder of the story but now it wasn't
all funny games it's like throughout
that those times there was a lot of
times of uncertainty a lot of times of
uh sadness and a lot of times of just
disarray and that just comes with part
of the lifestyle and part of the part of
just life and General mhm you you now
like the way that you're making it sound
is if though you did this all on your
own and you being a younger entrepreneur
who are the type of people that um who
are the type of people that were helping
you along the way build this stuff up
okay no I did not do it all on my own I
made the decision on my own to do it but
in order for me to actually be practical
and have the skill set and and have the
mindset to to even think big enough to
say that I can do something like this I
had to get the right people around me
and I tend to fall to people who were
older than me so I had mentors in my
life that would help me along the Route
so when I was 17 18 I had a mentor
called James Jackson and James Jackson
was a black entrepreneur in my area
where I looked up to him and said look
he's black I can do it you know in many
hoods and in many uh ghettos or in
poverished areas the younger guy looks
up to the guy that they most relate to
so if you're in the hood and the only
person that is doing well is the guy on
the Block selling drugs and he has a
nice car and he has this and he has that
he has the girl and everything and
that's all you see that's who you're
gonna look up to now I saw those that
type of person but I also saw the person
who was doing it right and I said to
myself I want to go in that direction
the person that's doing it right the
person that's also black the person
that's that's that grew up like myself I
want to do it just like that now at the
time he was a struggling entrepreneur
but look he was paying me right at the
time $500 was like a lot of money to me
getting paid more than $8 an hour you
are balling so I saw that and I'm just
like man I want to hang around him and I
and I got the opportunity to I was in
the back of his office um I was working
working for him and I was working at a
store that he worked in the back office
running a few of his stores and I would
just go to the back of of the the store
which was his office and I would say
what are you doing and he'd be like I'm
doing payroll and I would say okay
that's cool like what is payroll oh
payroll is this is when you have
employees and you pay your employees
okay awesome awesome what does that look
like oh this is a system that we use let
me show you boom boom boom boom oh well
he'll also show me how how his company
is expanding now when you expand you got
to hire more employees okay let me see
the interview process people will come
into the store I work I work the front
end which was the actual Store working
the computers and having the phones and
the the cases out but in the back was
the actual headquarters so people will
come in through the store go to the back
and be interviewed so I would see that
process I would also see the process of
people going to the back to be fired I
saw the whole entire process and within
a year I had the courage and I had the
know all to actually run my own cell
phone store now when I started my cell
phone store realized that I still had
the right people around me giving me the
direction or mentoring me when I needed
the information or needed help okay so I
would suggest that if you're trying to
level up you got to find a mentor
someone who can show you the ropes
okay now uh I used to like you know when
you say cell phones that's how I started
my career because uh
um you know I was an entrepreneur at
that time when I was 17 18 19 around
that age uh a group of us I was in I was
I was a rapper Believe It or Not folks I
was uh I was doing rap and um you know I
had my rap crew and you know I had this
dream of becoming a successful you know
entrepreneur um but I needed money and I
didn't have an education I I didn't
graduate high school so um I I started
my first thing uh in telecommunications
and made 40 Grand that first year and I
was like man that's a lot of money
godamn it you know cuz it's all
commission right uh but you know I I
kind of I I you know I it took me years
to kind of break out of retail and sales
and stuff like that um because I didn't
really know how to how to really get
into my own thing um but I know with
managing several of these stores that
starting a cell phone company is not
it's not cheap cheap you need you need
to buy inventory of phones expensive
phones like the iPhone and there's
little to no margin on those phones so
where did you get the money to to start
a cell phone um uh store and then to
grow it to four
stores so when I was uh maybe maybe at a
young age I don't know I was young but I
I developed the system that allowed me
to save money because I realized that
every week I was getting paid $3 to $500
and I had no money by the next paycheck
and I and I saw this vicious cycle of
$300 to $500 on Friday next Thursday I'm
down at zero and it was a vicious cycle
of paycheck to paycheck I'm seven I'm 17
at the time 16 17 18 and I don't have
any bills you know I don't even I don't
think I paid my cell phone bill but I
liked cash I love the money so and I
like having it so I realized my problem
was that I was seeing money and
realizing when I saw money I would spend
money and I would see it on my my my
cell phone app right so what I did was I
hid my savings account away from my from
my um what do you call this my my mobile
app I saved my my I what do you call it
I hid my savings account and then I had
a bank account that was far away from me
out of my reach so Bank of America was
my main account account that I would use
on a regular basis and then after that I
would have an account a a far account
that was out of my reach that had a
checking and savings account and I would
ask my employer to to send my money
parts of my money to this account to
these accounts and my my savings account
I would put a little money stashed away
in my savings account that I had no
access to because it was hidden so when
I got paid $300 what actually showed up
in my bank account was 120 when I got
paid 500 what actually showed up in my
bank account was 270 you understand and
I would just start saving money
unconsciously because all I knew was I
got paid oh yeah what did the rest of
money go and my savings but you never
touch that money after a year or two of
doing this I think I had like $7,000
remaining um when the when the
conversation came to open up the cell
phone store I I went to all my accounts
and I realized okay dang I had seven
Grand what am I going to do with it
I'mma open up the cell phone store now
uh you're you are you are 100% right
dude one iPhone one iPhone could cost
$850 if you if you only have $7,000 you
can only buy like eight iPhones and
that's your whole entire store so I
didn't go that route I took the route of
hustling which was taking the cheap
phones like when I tell you the cheap
cheap phones my inventory cost was 900
my first order of inventory I think was
like $900 and the rest of the money went
to organizing my company uh setting up I
didn't have LLC at the time I was I was
a so proprietor I didn't I I was going
through um through a mask a mask EIN
number to protect my my Social Security
but I didn't go you know go the LLC
route and I paid rent for a month and a
half so the month and I think like a
security deposit which was like
$1,500 and I had a few dollars remaining
to buy accessories and to buy a laptop I
I and I spent the whole entire $7,000
within a few within a few weeks of
opening up the cell pH store and all I
knew that I had to focus on was paying
rent the next month I ordered nine
phones okay it was nine phones Paulo is
in the Paulo Chavez is in here right now
is in the is in the Facebook live he was
part of the team when I first opened up
those cell phone stores so I I started
the store with nine phones nine cheap
phones all at less than $100 a pop
flipped those phones got the profit kept
the profit to pay rent to keep on
Growing Up growing the business so it
was profitting back into the business
profiting back into the business growing
the business eventually to one day I can
get an iPhone the and the way that the
story was when I actually started
bringing iPhones into into my business
was um I built a relationship with a
supplier and I said can you give me net
which is you sent me the iPhones you
don't charge me until I sell them in 30
days and I'll pay you back your part in
30 days and and that's how I started
growing I I got
credit so okay you got credit now man
that seems like wow like you just you
you you saw the opportunity you you
pounced on it and like you said like all
the costs you broke it down because I
mean I was in that industry I managed a
few stores you know inventory and
especially inventory that's cheap
inventory some of that stuff
just oh I hear myself but um you know
you got the accessories sitting on the
wall and don't move anywhere um so and
then you got cheap phones that maybe not
a lot of people want to buy how did you
flip those phones like what how did you
you know push cheap products on people
so that you can get to that next level
where did you get the Sal skills from
all right well let me let me rephrase
the word it wasn't cheap products it was
inexpensive phones there this is there's
price ranges and where I'm from it's an
area where you have either drug dealers
or you have people who can't afford the
highend products so they spend $100 on
the phone right and the $100 phone
includes the you know the the the the
the the phone and the service right so
the cost for the first month of service
was literally probably zero dollars
which meant that in my business I just
so you know Ryan I did prepaid phones I
didn't do po uh postpaid and I think
what you're talking about is more on the
postpaid uh postpaid carriers right
right now I did prepaid so there's a
little bit higher profit margin but just
on on the front end not the back end
postpaid you have more money on the back
end and that's just between you and I
because we both know the industry right
so prepaid cheap cheap entry um
inexpensive entry but it's still a
business I didn't have accessories on
the wall I had a cart in the mall it all
started at a cart not not even actual
store I didn't get my first store until
six months after so it was a it was a
cart in the mall so the it was very
inexpensive for me to start I had to
hustle now how we started selling was um
greeting customers I have I have a
technique where I can get a customer who
say 50 feet away from me to get them to
come over here and I will give you that
technique right now but it's for your
viewers and I've never done this on a
Facebook live before but I'm G do it for
your viewers because it happens it
happens in real life so this is what I
would do I would whisper so I would I
would do just
this and I would look at the person as
if I'm saying
something and and then say they say what
I say no what I was saying I I would
talk loud and I would drift my voice
down so what I was saying was when you
come and they be like what did you say
and when they get actually closer to me
I was saying I at a cell phone store
what phone do you have and they be like
I have an iPhone 6 and I'm gonna pretend
like I don't know what iPhone 6 is right
so they would be like I have an iPhone 6
I was like iPhone 6 you have it with you
and I would look at it at the wallet the
purse or whatever they they're holding
and they'll be like yeah and they'll
show it to me I I say let me see that
and I'll grab it out of their hands and
I would look at the phone like this I'll
say oh iPhone 6 I would grab it keep
holding on to it and bring it to my car
and put it behind my computer and now
I'm doing my pitch I'm 19 years old
teaching people how to do that I grab it
put it behind my computer now I'm doing
my now you would have some [ __ ]
people that are like give my [ __ ]
phone back and and and I and I'll give
them the phone back but you have some
people who are actually listening and
then after that do my pitch and I'll
sell them on something else so where did
you get those those those skills from I
mean like I I was in sales even from
when I was 12 so you kind of learn from
watching other people but like was it
just you being really hungry and just
trying to find multiple ways of of of
getting that getting that dough or you
know like how did you how did you get
that smart to be able to you know to
kind of wheel them into um listening to
you and talking to
you I I was mentored by
somebody who was my manager because
remember I was working at a Metro PCS
before I went on my own spot so I was
already selling phones and that's part
of the strategy that you needed to to to
to to sell phones and now in addition
addition to that someone taught me the
whisper technique right they taught me
the whisper technique but after the
whisper technique I I had to figure out
how do I get them to stay because they
would come to me with the whisper after
the whisper technique and then they
leave I think I froze am I Frozen you're
not
frozen okay I hope hey I need y to
comment I need y'all to comment I I need
I know you're like you know you like
like I know you like the story but I
need y'all to comment show some love
show some love at the bottom say what's
up Andy show some love at the bottom now
so I learned I learned about this
technique The Whisper right and after
the whisper I I did my own type of uh
finessing into it where I got people to
stay by taking their phone and placing
it behind the register U not allowing
them to take the phone back so now if if
you are in the mall walking and someone
does this to you and they they you're
you're actually there you're actually
there to take your phone you're about to
be sold another thing that I would do if
I don't have the phone in my hand I
would do this I would say man I got
something just for you turn around and
do this and never look back if you look
back that means you are not confident
the most confident person in the in the
sales negotiation wins so you got to
turn around and keep walking as if
they're walking behind you and you know
like some people might not follow you
that's okay just turn around and boom as
soon as you start walking what happens
is that people people are like am I am I
really going to follow this guy like
he's not and and they walk behind me and
that's what I would do the pitch now I
got them to my zone into my store okay
that's what I would do wow that's crazy
and I think you like you're pretty good
at sales and I mean and I and I and I
can tell you
firsthand um in uh coming into what I I
think I was in one of your
lives and you said you you you saw me in
theat and you're like my man Ryan Perez
Ryan Perez what's going on my man and
then you're like I got a book just for
you and you signed it and everything and
he's like $29.99 or whatever the thing
is and you know you had your sales pitch
but you know I when I saw that I was
like man that reminds me dude I'm still
waiting for you to buy the book
man I was like you know what cuz it it
what the way that you made it sound like
I was going to in it for free and I was
like man that is so nice of this guy
like he signs the book and like you know
but but I I said to myself I said to
myself um you know I'm like that reminds
me of when I was younger and just the
you know the cleverness but you also you
know your energy and your confidence and
stuff like that so I was like man one of
these days I want to get you on the show
because I think people really you know
people really need to understand a guy
like yourself because it doesn't seem
like this this this hunger is going to
go away I mean you you seem really
hungry you know to reach you know
plateaus in your life so I commend you
on some of those strategies what were
you gonna say I didn't mean to to
interrupt
you no I'll be I'll be sure to send you
the the Paypal invoice after this
live but um so yeah now
um that being said so you you've kind of
moved from cell phones now what happened
afterwards um you know how did you get
into writing your own book and and
getting into this next
level yeah yeah so so after doing the
cell phone business I did this so now my
company's name was called progression
Wireless right and the reason I called
it progression was because I come from
an area where people weren't really
focused on like goals and dreams and
aspirations and I was the only one and
it seemed to me like I was preaching to
a lot of people so I I decided like yo I
could if I open up my own business I
could have people come into my business
and my business would be responsible for
a lot of people having that mindset of
getting better that's what that's what
my dream was that's what my goal was
imagine me having a whole bunch of
employees who were just focused and
driven as much as I was that that
company would move as a unit very
quickly very fast and and and it would
explode that company right a company
focused on progression so that's why
it's called progression Wireless now
what I realized was this not everyone
cared about progressing majority of
people actually came into my company
just for a paycheck and I was shocked I
had one of my employees he told me he
was like thatan move as a are just here
for a paycheck like all they care about
is Friday's paycheck that what you're
gonna give them the money you're gonna
give them and I was just like nah no
this company's on progression not about
money it's on progression and once I
actually realized that was true I I
quickly like like what it would hit me
it hit me hard and I remember I remember
there was in in business you have peaks
in this valleys so when I tell you I had
a great month this was probably the best
month the most money my company has ever
made was in this one single month um and
it's just after we got you know we got
some different financing available and
the a new phone just launched and it was
available for people and people's credit
like it didn't matter what credit they
had they had bad credit good
credit so we made a lot of money and so
I was going through a serious Peak right
and then right after that boom a valley
so in business you have highs and you
have lows when you have a job and you
getting paid x amount of dollars per
hour your money is pretty consistent but
for the business it goes up and down so
so I had a month that I I went down and
dude I was 19 maybe 20 years old and I'm
like I don't really I don't have a
degree in accounting so I'm spending
money ridiculously dude I'm traveling
I'm buying people food I'm buying people
stuff and and I'm going to Vegas and I'm
renting cars dude there was a time that
my car wasn't doing well my car wasn't
doing hey Phil's in the building thank
you so much Phil Phil's Phil was a
partner in the cell phone business so
now I'm I'm I didn't have I didn't have
a car I remember my car my the car that
I purchased had a transmission problem
so I was renting cars and all different
types of cars Audi and all these
different type of cars and then I had
that Peak dude when I hit that Peak it
was like where did all my money go like
where did all my money go and I remember
I hit a peak and sales weren't coming in
the way that they were and I had I had a
u what you call payroll do and one of my
employee she has a she has a child and
she was like Andy she looked the way she
looked at me like Ryan when I tell you
this young woman
looked at me with like like like I don't
know like a like a bear cup she looked
at me she was like Andy I gotta I got to
feed my daughter and buy her a diapers
like I I I I depend on you for money and
it hit me dude I was like wow wow I
gotta go and get this money so what I
did was I hit the streets um in a legal
way I got phones from my store and went
on Craigs and I I was banging phones
sell selling phones on Craigs craigus
even though I had employees in the
stores I was selling these iPhones on
Craigs for the low and just taking that
profit reinvest pretty much how I used
to sell cell phones when I was in high
school that's how I used to hustle in
high school flip phones in the streets
like left and right left and right so I
did that and then I went back to my
office right I had an office that was in
a rural city that was a that so I can
manage all the stores and that was like
the central hub for inventory and all
that um so I go back to my office and
I'm sitting there by myself it's like 11
o'clock at night outside is Pitch Black
because this office is in in in a Ral
place my office manager wasn't there my
inventory manager wasn't there it was
just me by myself 11 at night I'm
looking at the bank account and I'm like
wow I'm I'm broke yep I'm broke I got a
few few few I got a few um few grand
left and I'm broke I'm I'm really bad
and I just go to the bathroom dude I I I
go to the bathroom because it was dark I
lay down on the floor I'm touch my feet
is along the sink to my left is to my
feet is touching the um the toilet to my
left is a sink to my right is the white
wall and behind me is a door and I'm
just laying down there and I'm just sad
dude I'm just sad and I and I was like
you know what I cried and after I cried
I got up I went to my car I went to the
car I was renting a at the time I had a
a silver car I was renting it got in the
car closed the door and just looked up
and I prayed to God right I just asked
God I was like God I pray to take take
my life to a whole another level to what
you want me to do and remove anyone
that's hindering My Success see I'm a
spiritual man I believe in God
wholeheartedly and I drove home I drove
home just just sad I probably was
playing sad music The Whole Nine Yards
pissed off you know just pissed off and
once I get home right I I plug in my
phone and I put on Pandora music and I
just lay down my face down on my bed and
I just laid down with my arms to the
side and um and what's what played was a
song called seven years from Lucas
Graham and the song goes once I was
seven years old my story was told so it
plays that song and I heard I'm
listening it and I'm and I'm visualizing
it so the story starts when the guy was
seven years old right and he skips ages
he goes from s to 11 from 11 to 20 and
he talks about you know his life when he
was that age so as when he was talking
about when he was when he talked about
when he was seven years old I connected
with him because I remember being seven
roaming the streets with my friends he
jumped to 11 and I remember me being 11
and I was shoveling the snow then he
jumped to 20 years old and I remember
being 20 because at the time I was 20
then he jumped to 30 and he talk talked
about his story at 30 and then he jumped
to 60 and he told his story at 60 and
then after that he he made a comment
that his dad only got 61 years to live
so in four minutes this guy told the
whole whole story of the life in four
minutes and I got up from that from that
like it wasn't a nap but I got up from
laying down like that and I said I need
to make a change to my life what am I
gonna do what am I going to do I need to
make a complete change because life is
too short I looked at life like this
right like this huge thing and I looked
at my life like this this so life is
just too short the world is like this
this is my life it's too short I need to
make a decision the next day I go to my
best friend Patrick's house and I say to
Patrick I said hey I'm sitting at the
kitchen table Patrick is is across from
me at the kitchen table my my feet is up
on a chair and I'm looking at Pat and
I'm saying like yo you want to make a
serious change in in
2016 and he's like what do you want to
do and I was like let's move like let's
get out of here I'm done let's get out
of here he said where you want to go
Andy the first thing that came to my
mind Los
Angeles when ever since I was young Los
Angeles has been like a goal for him
like a dream so I said Los Los Angeles
I've never been to Ellie at the time
I've never been there and he know he
said to me he said let's do it now we
had to we had to overcome some fear and
over and battle some you know negative
stuff in our life but we just did it we
just did it and it wasn't easy um if you
read my book that I go more into detail
of the stuff like how we overcame the
fear and what we had to do um and the
trials and tribulations that we had
because it wasn't easy you know Patrick
didn't want to go there was a time that
I didn't want to go because I was scared
it's a big change in our life but how we
did it it's in the book no more aage
book.com now when I'm you I plug right
you I I love the plug I love it you know
but here let me tell you something you
know you're the first person to really
you're you're like you know just as a
compliment you're you you have a really
good demeanor about your business and
the fact that you plug your book so CA I
I'm here like what what happened I'm
here shedding tears in the background
like once I was seven years
old like I'm like shoot 20 years I'm
like so captivated and then I gotta to
go buy the book so look like I'm G have
to buy the book after all um so that
that's awesome but um now can I we're
going to dial back a little bit
because I keep on the one theme that I
see is that you are you have been really
hungry
and I'm going to go to a story of mine
not going to talk too long cuz this is
about you um and I love the link the
link shows up on the screen you guys can
go purchase the book no more average
this is this is awesome so Andy you seem
to be very hungry for Success now I was
hungry for success but you know why
because my mom was uh you know she was
living she was living minimum wage she
had three children you know um and she
was a single mom you know that that
whole story that you will see on
Lifetime and um I went to school I
didn't really have you know I was going
down the wrong path and I was hungry for
Success because I didn't have nothing
and I was hungry hungry for Success
because I see other people that didn't
have anything and that scared the Jesus
out of me you know but everybody has a
story but what were the things that you
were observing in your childhood that
would make you so hungry because I have
kids I have friends that aren't hungry
you know I have friends that grew up
with a silver spoon in their mouth I had
kid I had friends that you know had
their parents two parents in the home
and didn't AIT witness abuse and all
that stuff because like I wanted money
because I wanted to run away from the
abuse that I was having at home with my
mom right so what caused you to be so
hungry man you know I think I think at a
at a young age right I just said to
myself wasn't fair I went my my parents
like now that I'm older I understand the
financial things that my parents went
through when I when I was younger CU at
the time I remember my dad it was like
you got to go to college and you got to
be a doctor like me I'm a I went to
college and I went to school for medical
and your mom is in in the medical field
and and I thought like for a moment that
we were Rich dude I we're rich my my
parents are rich
and I didn't realize like how much they
sacrific to try to get me the best
education to try to put me through to
get me around the best people right I
went to Catholic school for um up all
the way until 8th grade I went to
private school you know they hustled for
that hours on hours on and I now I
understand why I spent so much time in
daycare was because they were working to
be able to pay for my private school you
know so I learned that you got to work
for what you want they never gave me
anything they gave me they gave me the
the a bed to sleep in and the the the
necessity of food to eat and they gave
me water you know they gave me a shelter
so like they they didn't give me
anything past that and now I had friends
because now I'm in private school I have
friends around me who do have a lot
right who like their parents are like
dude private school we'll pay we'll pay
the whole school year we'll pay the
whole year tuition right now you know
what I'm saying my my parents were like
we'll pay every month as as much as we
can or late for your school payment
please don't kick my son out you know so
they they so I saw what my friends had
and it was like wow now I I I understand
if I went to a public school this is the
honest truth and my this is my belief
now that now that I'm thinking about
this if I went to a public school and I
saw a lot of the people around me didn't
have much I would like oh this is normal
we all don't have much but at a young
age I saw that like why can't I have an
Xbox mom can I can can you buy me an
Xbox like my friend does no we can't do
that okay can I have Nike Air Forces Dad
no we can't do that well what can I have
then all my friends have one have
something but I don't have damn so I was
pissed off so I was like I I I'll get it
myself I'll go get it myself don't worry
about it and it all started at a young
age dude it all started so when I got to
public school and high school now I
noticed that I had a drive in a tenacity
that many of my peers didn't have and I
just kept on going with it because I
found that innately at a young age when
my when I was pretty much broke going to
rich people school and hanging out rich
people so therefore I just look like
that was normal so my standards are
normal like my standards was raised by
being around these type of people so it
forced me so now I just learned
something and going back in my story
when you hang around the right people
your standards to start uh start being
raised if I hang around like I hang
around a whole bunch of business owners
so like to not have your own business in
my Social Circle is like like what
what's going on with you you know you
don't have your own business you know
what I'm
saying yeah and and I I I I was through
that same thing because I would see my
friends driving the cars they got the
girls in the car and here I got like you
know this is like you know n two year
2000 and I got baggy baggy jeans and you
know no bus fair and I'm seeing people
drive off in their cars and i' be
walking home and I'm like one of these
days I'm going to show yall one of these
days I'm going to show y'all one of
these days I'm going to show yall so
that's why people cuz like anyone that
knows me on the hustle Zone knows I work
hard from when I wake up until I go to
bed and my mentor always told me he says
you know work is a blessing work is a
blessing and if you have the ability to
work you know you can always find a way
to take care of yourself you know what I
mean you just have to work hard so you
know I commend you for you know just you
know recognizing at a very young age
that if you want to if you want
something serious in your life that um
you know you have to work hard for it
and the fact that you can look back at
age 22 it didn't take me till like I was
28 to look back at my parents and not
blame them for my shortcomings and the
fact that you learned it like earlier in
your in your in your career you know
that's brilliant it's not it's not
really like that it's like right now
dude like like right now it's like
probably probably I Look To be honest
like I texted my father um recently and
I was just like you know like although
back then I hated you for the stuff that
you did I love you so much because I
understand like why you have to do what
you have to do you know I understand
like why you weren't there a lot of the
times like I remember going to bask and
I still tear up dude I I'm not even
[ __ ] with you I still tear up because
I remember going to basketball games and
my parents weren't there like they had
to work dude and it's like to this day
dude I'm getting this money so I so they
can they can live the life that they
want to live I'm doing the things so
they can live the life that they want to
live because when I was young dude they
they were at work they were always
working man like it's they're always
working I'm at date I go I leave home at
7:30 in the morning I I get picked up to
5:00 pm and by 5:00 P PM everybody's
tired because my parents are tired
because they work so you know what am I
gonna eat oh go make yourself some ramen
noodles like ramen noodles is normal to
me you know what I'm saying like I
didn't know we were broke it's just
ramen noodles was like that's food so
you go make yourself some ramen noodles
and then you know so like they weren't
there and I realize now it's because
like dude they had to work they have to
grind look if you have a child right now
man right now all the things that you do
for your child is gonna is gonna propel
them in a certain direction in the
future all the things that I do to this
day right at this day is because of how
I was raised as a child I now I'm in the
Hampton right and what was it like
yesterday night me and me and my
business associate Rob we leave the
house that we're at and we go to um some
pizza spot down the street and we're
talk I'm talking to the pizza owner here
relationships okay understand that the
the the connection in my story with
relationships relationships so I'm
talking to the pizza owner and he tells
me like since he was a young since his
son was young he showed his son a lot of
money the pizza owner would have like 10
grand in the under table counting
Counting money at from the pizza owner
restaurants and he would show his son
like this is money 10 grand you know so
what that did for that young boy it
showed his standard of living your
standard of living is have a lot of
money and on top of that the father
would have his son uh sweep and and mop
the floor and do the cash register and
the whole nine yards of the business and
he would also have his son think bigger
talk about talk about um ideas of
thinking bigger now what happened to his
son his son is now 29 years old and his
son's a millionaire makes more than his
father because at a young age this young
boy saw his standard being raised than
his his his his Circle his standards
raised and her his daughter is doing the
same thing the the pizza owner's
daughter is doing something very well
gets paid most more than the average
American because their standards at a
young age was raised so the the
environment that I grew up in and all
the little bits of information dude
that's why I am the way I am today does
that make sense yeah that makes sense so
before we go to our second round of
questioning um you know the last
question is you got to meet Les Brown
how did you get to meet
him
um okay
so sales sales is an important aspect in
your life and you got you have have to
if you're working a retail job I'm so
grateful that I made the I made the move
and the shift out of the cell phone
business into like a hardcore sales
position because although the cell phone
is retail sales it doesn't cut it I
suggest that everyone everyone go into
something that's hardcore sales like you
got to prospect you have to find your
customer and the reason I suggest that
people do that is because it will
actually help you with your life and the
goals and and the things that you want
that other people have okay so so when I
moved from Los Angeles when I moved from
Rhode Island to Los Angeles I I got a
job working as a copier salesperson
sales rep and this job required me to
get in my own car and drive to different
businesses and knock knock knock on so
many doors to find out first who has a
copy machine and second how am I going
to sell them a new one if they already
have one okay okay and it was very hard
and what I learned from from that
business was persistence and
perseverance and just going after it
persistence perseverance and going after
it so if I had a prospect who had a Cofe
machine and I had a reason to sell them
a new one how do I get that deal when
they're focused on running their own
life they're focused on their own
business and the first that comes up to
their mind is not a copy machine so I
got to make a copy machine the top of
their mind it's called top of Mind
awareness so I would have to be
persistent just always show up hey how
are you that's actually how I got my
girlfriend just keep showing up hey how
are you so afterwards you know you you
knock knock on the door knock knock boom
find one keep showing up no get out of
my office Andy okay leave come right
back the next day hey I have I have an
offer for you you come back x amount of
times they're going to say okay let me
hear your offer and then if they don't
take the offer right then and there you
keep on coming back until they do that's
persistence perseverance and going after
it so I use the same thing to with with
a lot of my relationships and and what I
want right now on my Facebook page I'm
looking at a picture of me and Grant
Cardone um and I use the same same
strategy in order to get a relationship
with Grant and Grant and people like
Grant and people who are who are very
high um who are very high caliber they
appreciate that because they understand
that I'm what I am hungry if I keep
coming back I'm hungry you know I want
this and I and I show that off so to
answer your question right I joined the
Les Bron
Institute last year Les Brown has an
Institute where he teaches people how to
speak and it's and it's a separate
company but he teaches people how to
speak uh through online courses and
through certific live certifications
throughout the year and when I first
went there let me have you understand
this there's opportunity in the show up
so when I first went there realizing
there's opportunity when you show up I I
flew from LA to Miami to to see the Les
Brown Institute I wanted to see it
firsthand now I didn't have to be there
because majority of the the courses are
online everything's online I didn't have
to have to show up but I want to show up
to actually meet the people so I show up
on a random day I chose the cheapest
flight show up on a random day um and I
I'm I'm in there shaking people's hands
hey how are you how are you how are you
meeting all the sales people and the CEO
is there I shook hands with the CEO
the President's Day I shook hands with
the president um and then ironically by
strike of God by the grace of God Les
Bron happens to be in Florida now Les
Bron travels throughout the country but
Les Bron happens to be in Florida and
after the fact that Les Brown's in
Florida I think he was doing a gig in
Florida he just happens to be in Fort
louderdale that's where the the office
was and now even though he's in for lale
he happens to show up the same day the
same time I'm at the office he walks in
with a white T-shirt blue sweatpants and
he looks at me out of nowh he says young
man you he touching my face he's wiping
something on my face I had no idea he
was wiping a white piece of lint I had
on my face I thought he was telling me
my beard was like like I had I didn't
have a lot of facial hair like he does
so I thought he was telling me a joke
but he was like young man you you look
like me when I was younger and he made a
joke I'm taking this off your face and I
was like come on Les like this is not
it's it's not dirt it's actually facial
hair and I was making a joke but he was
like no you have something on your face
and I was like come on man I got nothing
come on man I was out I'm shocked dude
I'm mesmerized I'm mesmerized I'm
tripping right now and he's like no dude
you have something on your face and he
walked away he
walked like no dude you have something
in your face I look at my face and I
realized it's something white there a a
white piece of L on my face he walked
away I'm like oh no I lost the
opportunity
But but so I kept on showing up to to to
places where I knew that I had an
opportunity to build relationships with
the right people I understand in order
for you to level up you got to build
relationships so I kept on showing up
eventually that I started building a
relationship with the right people and
the right people helped me level up and
so on and so forth and the rest is
history
wow folks if you guys haven't shared
please share um now because I mean this
was really great first part of the
interview we're going to go through our
lightning round in a few seconds but you
know um uh this show is brought to you
by
ww.bbc creative.com
um and branding jim.com so you
know oh man like Andy man this is what a
great story thank you for sharing so
much so we're going to go into our our
lightning round speed um or our speed
lightning round um and ask just you know
this is just a a question these are
questions that you know help us get to
know other sides of you so from a scale
to 1 to 10 how good are you at keeping
secrets I can't
say from scale from 1 to 10 I can't say
dude it's a
secret okay Michael Jackson or
Prince you said Michael Jackson or
Prince
yeah who was originally
black okay next
question next next question okay so um
Don or
dusk Don or
dusk don don oh don don don I know Don
is now
okay so what's your favorite
holiday dude I'm not really a holiday
person but Christmas because it's six
days before my birthday okay do you
snore yes uh place that you want to
travel the
most I gotta I still gotta finish the
United States so United States favorite
childhood TV show
Simpsons uh uh last Halloween costume
a black
guy cake or
pie cake
cheesecake do you ever post
inspirational quotes on social media of
course and um invisibility or super
strength super
strength is it wrong for a vegetarian to
eat animal crackers
no okay I'm tell I'm
tell
so I'm posting that on Facebook
man you created that one no no these are
just pre-made uh lightning round
questions
so uh Andy thank you so much um how can
we find you my brother
Andy yo just find me on my Facebook Andy
dat uh I think it's facebook.com
andate just find me I want to connect
with everyone who watches this and tell
me what your thoughts were so far
message me on Facebook look I got my
Facebook open right now I want to
message you right now so find me on
Facebook and I want you to say hey that
was a great interview and let's start
from there awesome and what did you
think about being on the hustle Zone
dude the hustle Zone was dope it was it
it was great you know you had you have a
different setup than many other
interviews that I've done and I love
yours I love your show man oh awesome
and so we got before we close out we
have one more tradition that we do on
the hustle zone so I do a call and
response um so I say welcome to the and
I need you to scream as loud as you can
hustle Zone but it has to be loud okay
so I'm going to do it in one two three
welcome to the hustle Zone
but but you got to you got to yell it
man we got to feel the we got to feel
the soul the passion the fire the hunger
so let's do one more dude it's it's
midnight I'm in the house with other
people come on manome know we I I had I
had people do it with their kids they
had newborns all kinds of things so you
have it's one the last tradition they'll
have to forgive me they can blame me so
one more time welcome to
the hustle Zone
well thank you so much man uh so Andy
man uh and then make sure when when when
is your book coming out again December
22nd when I actually get my physical
copy I'm gonna do a Facebook live but
December 22nd you'll be able to get your
book at no more average but right now if
you go to no more aage book.com you can
order it I'm gonna ship it to you before
anyone else gets it okay awesome so no
more average
book.com folks he said it best no more
a.com thank you so much Andy no more
aage book.com thank you so much Ryan
yeah no problem wow what a great
interview right folks like he gave you
everything and you think you know
because like that's why with success it
doesn't really matter what age you are
what sex you are what race you are
everybody has their own story and this
is why we do the hustle Zone
because um we want to collect stories
like like this and added to our
repertoire my biggest takeaway of
tonight's story was um you know just
being in the place where you want to see
your success you know he put himself in
positions where you know he could see
more success his parents put him in
situations where he can see the success
so what were your guys's biggest um
biggest takeaways of the show guys uh
make sure you guys check me out on
hustlez own.tv to see other interviews
and uh make sure you go to Brandy
jim.com for unlimited graphic design
make sure you go to bcreative uh.com and
and and and and and one more time go to
our
gofundme.com
hustle Zone hyphen TV and donate a
little something something um so that we
can continue doing this on a larger
scale so that we can travel and meet
entrepreneurs like Andy and uh record
their stories and put it part of the
documentary my name is Ryan Perez I am
the hustle Zone King I am RP to God and
I will talk to you guys later
[Music]